<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Music Reviews - Bottle Imp Productions</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/music-reviews/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/music-reviews</link>
	<description>Independent Record Label - Ambient / Post-industrial / Neoclassical</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 14:44:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/bottleimp-144-120x120.png</url>
	<title>Music Reviews - Bottle Imp Productions</title>
	<link>/category/music-reviews</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Top Ten from AMNION for 2013</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/top-ten-amnion-2013</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/top-ten-amnion-2013#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Roderick Price]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 20:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[antonymes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben lukas boysen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boards of canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diaphane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Felix Gebhard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julia Kent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rafael Anton Irisarri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steven Price]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tzolk'in]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1937005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ben Lukas Boysen – Gravity I greatly admire the work of Ben Lukas Boysen. I have followed his sound design output closely both under his own name and as his moniker Hecq. Gravity is truly a beautiful release that presents&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/top-ten-amnion-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Top Ten from AMNION for 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ben Lukas Boysen – Gravity</strong><br />
I greatly admire the work of Ben Lukas Boysen. I have followed his sound design output closely both under his own name and as his moniker Hecq. Gravity is truly a beautiful release that presents Boysen at the top of his game. This album reveals a deeply personal and mature direction into Boysen’s modern classical mastery.</p>
<p><strong>Antonymes – There can be no true beauty without decay</strong><br />
I greatly anticipate every new release from Antonymes. With his latest release Ian M Hazeldine paints majestic landscapes with his textures, field recordings and orchestrated pianos and strings. The atmosphere Hazeldine conjures up is all immersive and all consuming. Hauntingly beautiful and extremely uplifting, ‘There can be no true beauty without decay’ is pure sonic nourishment from start to finish.</p>
<p><strong>Tzolk’in – The sixth sun</strong><br />
I’m a big fan of Gwenn Tremorin’s work as Flint Glass so naturally I was always going to enjoy the joint between himself and Empusae on their tribal, industrial outfit Tzolk’in. The sixth sun is an epic release for Tzolk’in, keeping true to form with plenty of heart pounding percussion by Nicholas culminating with the ethereal atmospheres and slicing electronics from Tremorin.  As with their previous releases the Mayan themes in ‘the sixth sun’ are strong as you ride into the end of days, but what a ride it is!</p>
<p><strong>Julia Kent – Character</strong><br />
I cannot say enough great things about this release, Character is such a satisfying and rich body of work. For me the title of the album supports Kent’s foreboding cello work acting as the main protagonist in the loose and imaginative narrative. Each track weaves a story like a vignette from a movie scene that develops and builds with cinematic lifts and arcs. At the moment I find myself listening to a lot of modern classical music with heavy focus on cello and I get excited to hear new articulations on the sounds this instrument can produce, Character was my stand out album choice for this reason.</p>
<p><strong>36 – Shadow Play</strong><br />
Dennis Huddleston produces some of the finest quality minimal drone scapes under his ambient project ‘36’ [three-six]. I’ve followed his work for some time and have been amazed at how much his work has developed and progressed. Back in March 2012 Huddleston released his cinematic ambient epic ‘Lithea’, up until mid 2013 this album was still on my regular rotation, I didn’t think he’d top this release. After a year off production and with some soul searching Huddleston released ‘Shadow Play’ an album that takes the sound of 36 into new territory, the lo-fi ambience is soothing, the instrumentation is crisp. Overall ‘Shadow Play’ is beautifully produced release that is conceptually strong and offers a deeply satisfying listening experience.</p>
<p><strong>Diaphane – Lifeforms</strong><br />
I find it hard to categorize the work of Diaphane into any one genre. The music here is so varied and multidimensional that to simply call it IDM or Electronic seems to downplay the detail and delicacy of its sound design. Lifeforms is in itself a lifeform, one that builds and grows through micro frequencies and rhythmic syncopated beats. I particularly enjoy the balance found between the warm piano melodies, strings and synth washes against the colder noise blasts, glitched beats and whiplash bass lines.  I really liked Diaphanes debut album Samdhya but I think I like Lifeforms even more, probably because I find myself nodding my head to this release when playing loud in the car. I’m keen to hear where he goes next.</p>
<p><strong>Rafael Anton Irisarri – The unintentional sea</strong><br />
This album was such a delight when I first listened to it and it still continues to impress and inspire me. The unintentional sea, like many of Irisarri’s work, reflects a fascination with landscape, space and atmosphere. Drawing inspiration form the true story about the Salton Sea redirection, Irisarri combines field recordings with cinematic drones and minimal type classical instrumentation. Piano strikes bounce around the sound sphere while subtle frequencies build and distort over time. Distant field recordings are highlighted in the background flickering, crackling and bubbling away while deep bass thuds and rumbles hover below the surface. There is a feeling of heart filling warmth that comes from the orchestration of these elements. This complements beautifully the overwhelming sense of melancholy permeating this release. I truly adore this release.</p>
<p><strong>Steven Price – Gravity OST</strong><br />
Regardless of whether you like the film or not there is no denying that Steven Price’s soundtrack is a sensational album, one that compliments the full dynamic range of the ambient landscape and fear full tension presented in the movie.<br />
I did enjoy hearing the soundtrack against the film and experiencing it in surround sound is the only way in my opinion. There are some beautiful cinematic moments and orchestral arrangements in this release, some almost minimal pieces. I gotta say I’m a sucker for the rhythmic synthesized string motifs that Price uses to build tension, this gets the heart pounding. I’m also impressed with how this release stands apart from other blockbuster soundtracks, notably the use of sound design in the soundtrack itself but also the absence of big hit percussion and not relying heavily on standard Hollywood clichés to deliver an engaging and emotional result.</p>
<p><strong>Felix Gebhard – Gone for walks</strong><br />
Field recording is something I love to do whenever I can spare the time. With his release on Tessellate Recordings Felix Gebhard has produced a collection of tracks that read more as sonic postcards. I myself like to explore concepts that surround ‘sonic identity’ and the art of reflecting time and place through field recordings. The field recordings captured are taken on walks in and around Langendorf, Germany during 2011. Gebhard weaves a variety of instruments into these recordings producing an extraordinary rich and evocative sonic tapestry. To enrich the experience further Gebhard includes four postcards (one for each track) with a map of the walk on which recordings were made, with a specific location marked with a red &#8216;X&#8217;. All items are beautifully packaged in a handmade envelope.</p>
<p><strong>Boards of Canada – Tomorrows Harvest</strong><br />
I have a soft spot in my heart for the music of Boards of Canada. When I was just starting out toying with samplers, synths and software BoC were on constant rotation in my headphones. Tomorrows Harvest definitely keeps with their original sound but they have still managed to produce a fresh sounding album overall. Coming up with new and innovative album seems like a hard task for BoC being that they&#8217;ve kind of backed themselves into a corner with a sound that relies heavily on nostalgic references. All the same, I’ve greatly enjoyed this addition to the BoC catalogue.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:dt10111:playlist:3TxaTDBOfLswgtOUy93GQB" width="300" height="80" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/top-ten-amnion-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Top Ten from AMNION for 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/top-ten-amnion-2013/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Row Boat&#8217;s Top Ten for 2013</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/row-boats-top-ten-2013</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/row-boats-top-ten-2013#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark Wardale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 14:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[65daysofstatic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[M.I.A.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moshimoss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oceanus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olafur arnalds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preghost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[row boat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sigur Ros]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Gibbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Denim]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1935635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When musical worlds collide, here is my top 10 releases of the year. 10. ‘Corsicana Lemonade’ by White Denim White Denim released their 5th studio album this year, &#8216;Corsicana Lemonade.&#8217; In keeping with tradition, the album has that original progressive/psychedelic/jam&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/row-boats-top-ten-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Row Boat&#8217;s Top Ten for 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When musical worlds collide, here is my top 10 releases of the year.</p>
<p><strong>10. ‘Corsicana Lemonade’ by White Denim</strong><br />
White Denim released their 5th studio album this year, &#8216;Corsicana Lemonade.&#8217; In keeping with tradition, the album has that original progressive/psychedelic/jam session feel throughout. It&#8217;s one of the reasons this album flowed into my top 10 with a hard riff hook opening and unique song structures to the norm.</p>
<p><strong>9. ‘Sirens’ by Oceanus</strong><br />
Oceanus&#8217; debut album was an instant hit for me. For two people to release an album that interlinks with theme and music, and is as tight as it is, the work they put into this album deserves to be appreciated. I could rave about it all day, but really it&#8217;s one of those postrock releases you must hear for yourself, from start to finish.</p>
<p><strong>8. ‘Mantangi’ by M.I.A.</strong><br />
I&#8217;ve been a fan of M.I.A. since she came on the scene back in 2005. This album was released on her own label, N.E.E.T Recordings, so I was even more curious as M.I.A. is renowned for speaking her mind lyrically, which I do like in certain artists. I love this album. Combining those lyrics and adding the thick, attractive beats and melodies onto this selection of tracks, once again proved that whilst emphasising meaningful lyrics you can create a sexy beat too.</p>
<p><strong>7. ‘In Passing’ by Steve Gibbs/Cyrus Reynolds</strong><br />
Simply put, a beautiful collection of songs that just grip you all the way. I normally sit on a quiet moment with these songs as you are able to hear the background noises (the breathing and strain of the bow against the violin strings) that are every bit as  important as the instruments themselves.  I will dance and shout on the rooftops about it until i&#8217;m in my grave.</p>
<p><strong>6. ‘Ghost Story’ by Preghost</strong><br />
Preghost, also known as Kosuke Anamizu, released ‘Ghost Story’ this year.  It is a collection of what I guess I would call &#8216;dreamy electronica.&#8217; This debut alias of Kosuke (yes he has more alias&#8217;s) shot into my top 10 upon hearing track 2, “Snow Leopard.” That&#8217;s how good it really is. The overall theme of this album makes perfect sense from a listening point and is, for me, one of the ultimate chill out albums I&#8217;ve come across.</p>
<p><strong>5. ‘Holy Fire’ by Foals</strong><br />
Many people didn&#8217;t hear of Foals until this year. They&#8217;ve been around for some time, but this year they really cracked the indie market with the hard hitting and incredibly well written album &#8216;Holy Fire&#8217;. This album is one of my running albums. It&#8217;s constant, clever, melodic, sometimes heavy, sometimes softer. It&#8217;s complete, and it&#8217;s one for any kind of rock collection. As long as they don&#8217;t stray too far into the mainstream, they will keep producing great albums like this.</p>
<p><strong>4. ‘Kveikur’ &#8211; Sigur Ros</strong><br />
Wouldn&#8217;t be a top 10 without Sigur Ros. Everybody who knows me, knows how much respect I have for these guys. I have to admit I was worried about the direction they would take with their new work after Kjartan Sveinsson left the group. But Kveikur is a very, very solid album. It&#8217;s not my favourite of theirs, but, my god, they have written a fantastic set of tracks and created some new signature sounds, which is very admirable of them. They&#8217;re as solid as ever with songs like “Isjaki” and “Brennisteinn.”</p>
<p><strong>3. ‘For Now I Am Winter’ by Olafur Arnalds</strong><br />
And now for my second Icelandic artist, &#8216;For Now I Am Winter&#8217; by Olafur Arnalds. For me, this is quite simply the best work of his to date. What makes this album more special for me is the inclusion of Arnór Dan Arnarson, who is the front man of my favourite band, Agent Fresco. Beautifully composed piano pieces with minimal beats here and there, and the small orchestra of strings make this album a wonderful experience to listen to.</p>
<p><strong>2. ‘Endless Endings’ by Moshimoss</strong><br />
I told you Kosuke Anamizu had more than one alias, and here is his other, Moshimoss. For me, my top 2 was always going to be an ambient or a postrock. ‘Endless Endings’ is a spectacular ambient album put together so delicately with ethereal textures and a stunning arrangement of instruments. There is nothing complex in this album, but it&#8217;s so intelligently put together; and that’s what makes it so good. Take my word for it, it&#8217;s an album you must own.</p>
<p><strong>1. ‘Wild Light’ by 65daysofstatic</strong><br />
When you sit in the car with your wife, she turns to you and says, &#8220;this song is outrageously good. I love it!!!!&#8221; That&#8217;s when you have your album of the year. You see my wife, has great taste in music. We differ in some areas, but with ‘Wild Light’ there is no difference in opinion. It&#8217;s a masterpiece of postrock. Most postrock fans (I believe) would agree with me here. It, like many other of my favourite albums, will probably never ever leave my playlist. Melodic and powerful with offbeat arrangements, encapsulating guitars, heavy drum beats, if you looked up ghost-rock in the dictionary, you&#8217;d find a picture of the ‘Wild Light’ album cover next to the description.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:dt10111:playlist:2vgqQ2qLDKv6V3hgwAtvfR" width="300" height="80" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/row-boats-top-ten-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Row Boat&#8217;s Top Ten for 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/row-boats-top-ten-2013/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five from BLAERG for 2013</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/five-blaerg-2013</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/five-blaerg-2013#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Wehman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 15:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autechre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blaerg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boards of canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine drum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oneohtrix point never]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve moore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1894004</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For 2013, I struggled to even come up with 5 impressive releases and the results are quite vanilla. I find as time goes on my interest in my own musical pursuits makes attention to the work of others continually shrink.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/five-blaerg-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Five from BLAERG for 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For 2013, I struggled to even come up with 5 impressive releases and the results are quite vanilla. I find as time goes on my interest in my own musical pursuits makes attention to the work of others continually shrink. I didn’t dig deep, but suggestions are always welcome. Contact blaerg@gmail.com</p>
<p><strong>5. Machine Drum – Vapor City</strong><br />
While not reaching the dizzying heights of 2011’s Room(s), Machine Drum has reached an interesting and very accessible amalgamation of the best aspects of modern beat-driven music with Vapor City (somehow a loosely tied concept album that I don’t quite get). Conceptual aspects aside, these tracks exploit the simple premise of wonderfully catchy melodic ideas peppered with tasteful weirdness (vocal snippet manipulations), endorphin-releasing synths and restrained yet technically dazzling (footwork-tinged) breakbeat structures. There’s even a genuinely 80s-sounding hazy slow-jam in the way of “U Still Lie”.</p>
<p><strong>4. Oneohtrix Point Never – R Plus Seven</strong><br />
Leaving behind his (prolific, competent and enjoyable) late 70s/early 80s synth-ambient phase, Oneohtrix Point Never’s R Plus Seven strides confidently into the refreshingly plastic sounds of the early 90s. This worked especially well when paired live with digital animations by Nate Boyce when I saw him with Tim Hecker at the Walker Art Center in November.</p>
<p><strong>3. Steve Moore – Pangea Ultima</strong><br />
I’ve been a fan of Steve and his band Zombi for several years and despite a couple of lackluster EPs, this full-length from the end of the year stands out as a unique addition to his discography and demonstrates his continual exploration of the genre. On Pangea Ultima Steve strips things down to their bare minimal ingredients – and to great success. This cold refinement highlights interesting and complex polyrhythmic ideas in what I like to imagine an alternate 80s that never came to be.</p>
<p><strong>2. Autechre – Exai</strong><br />
Nothing much to say other than another great record from Autechre which demonstrates their ability to create new permutations of their sound while still retaining their identity.</p>
<p><strong>1. Boards of Canada – Tomorrow’s Harvest</strong><br />
After a long silence, BOC is back with their darkest and perhaps most minimal work yet. The guitars have been put away and the distant synth colors are back in full force, albeit more restrained. Works perfectly as a post-apocalyptic soundtrack.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:dt10111:playlist:5IzxetZ2dw4U8YHPT3wHka" width="300" height="80" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/five-blaerg-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Five from BLAERG for 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/five-blaerg-2013/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shadowjack&#8217;s Top Ten 2013</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/shadowjacks-top-ten-2013</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/shadowjacks-top-ten-2013#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shane Semler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 15:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black sun empire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celldweller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dj hidden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drum n bass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iamamiwhoami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[noisia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shadowjack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1894241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>My top 10 albums of 2013, in no particular order. Black Sun Empire &#8211;&#160;Variations on Black I&#8217;m a sucker for a good remix album. Not only is it great to hear new takes on already solid material, some times the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/shadowjacks-top-ten-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Shadowjack&#8217;s Top Ten 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My top 10 albums of 2013, in no particular order.</p>
<p><strong>Black Sun Empire &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Variations on Black</i></strong><br />
I&#8217;m a sucker for a good remix album. Not only is it great to hear new takes on already solid material, some times the results are better. I don&#8217;t think I can say these remixes are necessarily better but they are excellent. If you love DnB with a bit of Dubstep thrown in and Black Sun Empire, you can&#8217;t go wrong with this album. On a side note, looking at the remixers, many are artists I listen to but few of which actually released anything in 2013. Guys, get off your asses!</p>
<p><strong>Iamamiwhoami &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Bounty</i></strong><br />
The music is airy yet dense. I can&#8217;t make out the lyrics and I honestly don&#8217;t care enough to look them up. The vocals are just another instrument as far as I&#8217;m concerned. I find it impossible to seperate the music from the videos. Both the music and the images elevate the mundane and commonplace to an epic. Cheap cardboard sets and tube socks become castles and kings telling tales of death and rebirth. I&#8217;ve revisited the video album on YouTube more than a few times, and unusually for me, done nothing else but experience it and the previous album Kin, back to back. I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;ll be visiting it again in the near future.</p>
<p><strong>V V Brown &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Samson &amp; Delilah</i></strong><br />
I don&#8217;t think V V Brown is well known in the US but in the UK, she&#8217;s a pop star. And an odd one at that. Her previous album is rather bland pop mush with an odd tinge of Rockabilly and 60s retro. How she got from there to this, I can&#8217;t imagine. I always had a desire to see a pop artist wig out and do something totally unexpected and &#8220;out there&#8221;, imagine Justin Timberlake doing a Death Metal album. Samson &amp; Delilah Is such a rapid 180 from her older output, I&#8217;m surprised her fans didn&#8217;t get whiplash. This is smart, dark and dense, surprisingly meaty listening experience.</p>
<p><strong>Disasterpeace &#8211;&nbsp;<i>FEZ Original Soundtrack</i></strong><br />
I bought this soundtrack long before I played the game. Despite Disasterpeace&#8217;s incredible talent, it&#8217;s often betrayed by the tropes inherent to the retro indie game aesthetic. FEZ should be just another indie game and the soundtrack should be yet another competent but predictable, ironically retro chiptune background filler. But it so much more. Disasterpeace takes dirty, lowfi beeps a bloops and creates gorgeous, atmospheric soundscapes that build an entire world in the listener&#8217;s mind. This is the best thing he&#8217;s ever done. It&#8217;s a perfect soundtrack to an outstanding game.</p>
<p><strong>Solar Fields &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Origin # 02</i></strong><br />
Yet another dependably excellent release. I always know I can play any Solar Fields album and it will be highly polished, electronic chill. Predictability isn&#8217;t always a bad thing, especially when it&#8217;s predictably good.</p>
<p><strong>DJ Hidden &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Enclosed</i></strong><br />
I was introduced to Drum and Bass back in the mid 90s through Roni Size&#8217;s&nbsp;<i>Brown Paper Bag</i>&nbsp;music video. I had never heard anything quite like it then or since. And no, not this either. Anyway, at the time I listened to a lot of Industrial. Where Industrial was a clanking, rusty beast of layered sounds, Roni Size&#8217;s DnB was streamline, minimalist and polished to a sheen. So it&#8217;s interesting to see what happens when someone with an Industrial background does DnB. While his older albums were squarely in the DnB genre, Enclosed incorporates more Breakcore elements and ambient interludes. This tends to add a bit more clutter than I like. Even so, this album has wicked editing and production.</p>
<p><strong>Celldweller &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Celldweller 10 Year Anniversary Deluxe Edition</i></strong></p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: It was pointed out to me by Klayton on the official @celldweller Twitter account that the 10th Anniversary audio is exactly the same as the 2003 release. I listened to it on Spotify Unlimited which does NOT have a high quality stream option (that is for Premium only). If you care about sound quality, Spotify may not be a the best choice.</p>
<p>The first Celldweller album was so strong and Clayton was so busy, it took him 8 year to finally get around to releasing a follow up. This album ruined Industrial for me. The sound was such a fresh take on the Industrial genre only now are others catching up. The anniversary edition doesn’t really offer anything new, some tweaks here and there, mainly some of the synth lines are turned up in the mix. I don’t think the tweaks add anything new or necessary. The second discs has a bunch of b-sides and singles and unreleased material, all good stuff. This release is a reminder of just how great this album was and still is.</p>
<p><strong>Koan &#8211;&nbsp;<i>When The Silence Is&#8230;</i></strong><br />
How is it there are seemingly so many high quality, meticulously produced chill/downtempo artists? Is there a factory in China making this stuff? Is it one insanely busy guy recording all of it (maybe he&#8217;s in the studio next to Clayton of Celldweller). I don&#8217;t know but as long as someone keeps making it, I&#8217;ll keep listening.</p>
<p><strong>Amon26 &#8211;&nbsp;<i>Gravity Mako</i></strong><br />
Amon26 has two contrasting strains to his output. One is dark ambient, Industrial-esque horror soundtrack stuff, the other is highly melodic, bouncy and energetic chiptunes. It wouldn&#8217;t be unreasonable to mistakenly think they are from two completely different artists.&nbsp;<i>Gravity Mako</i>&nbsp;falls into the melodic, bouncy half. The common thread is that they both are gritty, distorted and lowfi. Amon squeezes a lot of atmosphere from very little. The efficiency of his work never ceases to amaze me. Bonus: check out his recently released&nbsp;<i>The Nimesta EP</i>.&nbsp;<i>Available here:&nbsp;<a href="http://amon26.bandcamp.com/album/gravity-mako" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">http://amon26.bandcamp./<wbr>com/album/gravity-mako</a>&nbsp;</i></p>
<p><strong>Noisia &#8211;&nbsp;<i>DmC Devil May Cry (Original Game Soundtrack)</i></strong><br />
Cool, Noisia did a game soundtrack and it&#8217;s awesome! It&#8217;s also not surprising considering the cinematic nature of their work. It might as well be a regular Noisia release. And you don’t need to play the game to appreciate, which is great, especially if you&#8217;re&nbsp;not a&nbsp;<i>Devil May Cry</i>&nbsp;fan.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:dt10111:playlist:5EJOTQqQvBUbLuQJZaM4Q9" height="80" width="300" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/shadowjacks-top-ten-2013" data-wpel-link="internal">Shadowjack&#8217;s Top Ten 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/shadowjacks-top-ten-2013/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Ten Albums of 2013 for Daniel</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/top-ten-albums-2013-daniel</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/top-ten-albums-2013-daniel#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 05:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ben lukas boysen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black mare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chelsea wolfe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girls names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lustmord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lycia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nick cave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olan mill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinkish black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[savages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zomby]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1775779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Its that time of year again! Here&#8217;s my short list of favorite albums from 2013. Should be noted that these are in no particular order, and it was difficult getting my list down to just ten. Also should be noted&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/top-ten-albums-2013-daniel" data-wpel-link="internal">Top Ten Albums of 2013 for Daniel</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Its that time of year again! Here&#8217;s my short list of favorite albums from 2013. Should be noted that these are in no particular order, and it was difficult getting my list down to just ten. Also should be noted I included no Bottle Imp releases, though 2013 saw some really strong releases.</p>
<p><strong>Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain is Beauty&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Haunting and beautiful. <a href="/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty" data-wpel-link="internal">Read my full review</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Ben Lukas Boysen, &#8220;Gravity&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>An extremely powerful record by one of my favorite composes and sound designers. Boysen&#8217;s gravity treads into striking new musical territories, including some pushes into postrock territory. Recommended for fans of Clint Mansell&#8217;s film scores.</p>
<p><strong>Lycia, &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Triumphant return of the 90&#8217;s ethereal standard bearer. <a href="/music-reviews/lycia-quiet-moments" data-wpel-link="internal">Read my full review.</a></p>
<p><strong>Olan Mill, &#8220;Hiraeth&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Breath-taking, heavenly strings and classical crescendos. Veers into some territories that reminds me of the pieces used in 2001: A Space Odyssey.</p>
<p><strong>Savages, &#8220;Silence Yourself&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Winner for my &#8220;Most hours played&#8221; award, a super potent gothic rock throwback. <a href="/music-reviews/savages-silence-yourself" data-wpel-link="internal">Read my full review.</a></p>
<p><strong>Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed to the Ground&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>An epic work that could be the soundtrack to a bad ass, early 80?s Sword and Sorcery flick. <a href="/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground" data-wpel-link="internal">Read my full review.</a></p>
<p><strong>Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Utter darkness from legendary ambient composer. <a href="/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power" data-wpel-link="internal">Read my full review</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Girls Names, &#8220;The New Life&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Another interesting rock act with a vintage sound that evokes Faith era The Cure.</p>
<p><strong>Black Mare, &#8220;Field of the Host&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Beautiful down-tempo ethereal music from Ides of Gemini vocalist. <a href="/music-reviews/black-mare-field-of-the-host" data-wpel-link="internal">Read my full review</a></p>
<p><strong>Zomby, &#8220;With Love&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Dark but minimal techno with an early 90&#8217;s vibe.</p>
<p><strong>Nick Cave and the Bad Seeds, &#8220;Push The Sky Away&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Extremely strong record by Nick Cave and crew, one their best in many years.</p>
<p><strong>Playlist</strong></p>
<p>This playlist contains a larger collection from more of my favorite albums of 2013.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:dt10111:playlist:4tXRPX6dSOn1ryZftLEUV6" width="300" height="80" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/top-ten-albums-2013-daniel" data-wpel-link="internal">Top Ten Albums of 2013 for Daniel</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/top-ten-albums-2013-daniel/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adrian Aniol, &#8220;Obscura&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 15:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obscura]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1770900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Obscura&#8221; is an original score composed by Adrian Aniol for a theatre production. This must have been a frightening production as the music is utterly dark, tense and horrifying. This music is scary in the same way the Penderecki compositions&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura" data-wpel-link="internal">Adrian Aniol, &#8220;Obscura&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Obscura&#8221; is an original score composed by <a title="Adrian Aniol" href="https://adriananiol.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Adrian Aniol</a> for a theatre production. This must have been a frightening production as the music is utterly dark, tense and horrifying. This music is scary in the same way the Penderecki compositions used in Stanley Kubrick&#8217;s &#8220;The Shining&#8221; is scary. Its completely suspenseful, and keeps you moving frame-by-frame, wondering what hides behind the next corner, or under the bed. Aniol is no stranger to dark compositions, but this one turns the darkness up to eleven. This is certainly worth the $5 USD it costs to download from his <a title="Bandcamp" href="https://adriananiol.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Bandcamp</a>. And while you&#8217;re there, listen to his other works as they are all similarly wonderful.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura" data-wpel-link="internal">Adrian Aniol, &#8220;Obscura&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drudge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinkish black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relapse records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sword and sorcery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1678189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The new album by Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221; is an epic work that could be the soundtrack to a bad ass, early 80&#8217;s Sword and Sorcery flick. This is heavy, drudge metal, layered with waves of vintage filter&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground" data-wpel-link="internal">Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new album by Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221; is an epic work that could be the soundtrack to a bad ass, early 80&#8217;s Sword and Sorcery flick. This is heavy, drudge metal, layered with waves of vintage filter sweeps that evoke images of battles, journeys to the underworld and heroic deaths. Amazingly, this album that sits so solidly in the area of doom metal is entirely devoid of any guitars. The music is entirely performed by a duo, one on a drum kit and the other on a rack of synthesizers. This album is still blisteringly heavy, and you never miss the guitars for a second. &#8220;Razed to the Ground&#8221; is highly dynamic, with incredible song structure.</p>
<p>The only unfortunate reality here is that Pinkish Black&#8217;s &#8220;Razed to the Ground&#8221; is not, in fact, the soundtrack to some early 80&#8217;s Sword and Sorcery epic. Here&#8217;s to hoping this obvious marriage could occur some day!</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/106472936&amp;color=000000&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground" data-wpel-link="internal">Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 20:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chelsea wolfe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1414360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s album &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221; is epic, bold, ethereal and beautiful. This is a full fledged, fully realized rock album, covering all the gothic torch-bearing attributes one could ever hope to find in one album. The instrument selection bounces&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty" data-wpel-link="internal">Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s album &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221; is epic, bold, ethereal and beautiful. This is a full fledged, fully realized rock album, covering all the gothic torch-bearing attributes one could ever hope to find in one album. </p>
<p>The instrument selection bounces around a fair bit song to song, but it does not distract from the cohesiveness of the overall composition. A few songs use pulsing electronics with programmed percussion, where others use organic drum kits. Strings ebb and flow and each song creates its own unique palette of sounds. </p>
<p>Each song has a sublime yet tenebrous quality to it, but it bounces around stylistically. The fourth track, &#8220;The Warden&#8221;, starts out with a pulsing electronic rhythm and slowly opens up into a song that would be at home on a 1980&#8217;s album by The Legendary Pink Dots. Except, of course, minus the enigmatic Edward Ka-spel and add the mysteriously haunting Chelsea Wolfe, whose ghostly voice carries the strength of the song. &#8220;The Warden&#8221; transitions into &#8220;Destruction Makes the World Burn Brighter&#8221;, a more up-tempo piece that would sit comfortably on the soundtrack for &#8220;Twin Peaks&#8221;. This type of surreal juxtaposition occurs a few times, and it is never jarring: The album moves on and you are pulled deep into Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s dark, haunted world. </p>
<p>Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221; is one of the very best albums of 2013. Its also one of the best from her own catalog, which is a formidable feat in itself, since all of her albums are similarly amazing. The strong composition, the strength of Wolfe&#8217;s voice and the extremely tight production push the album into remarkable territories. This is an album you&#8217;ll listen to on repeat.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 42px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1972857446/size=small/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/transparent=true/" seamless><a href="http://chelseawolfe.bandcamp.com/album/pain-is-beauty" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Pain is Beauty by CHELSEA WOLFE</a></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty" data-wpel-link="internal">Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jarboe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lustmord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maynard James Keenan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1396246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Lustmord&#8217;s &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221; is an appropriately potent album that departs musically from the drones that make up his previous albums. This album still has Lustmord&#8217;s signature drones and dark ambiance, but is accompanied by extremely rich vocal performances.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power" data-wpel-link="internal">Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.lustmord.com/" title="Lustmord" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Lustmord&#8217;s</a> &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221; is an appropriately potent album that departs musically from the drones that make up his previous albums.  This album still has Lustmord&#8217;s signature drones and dark ambiance, but is accompanied by extremely rich vocal performances. The vocals are provided by an assortment of guest vocalists including Aina Skinnes Olsen, Jarboe (from Swans), Maynard James Keenan (from Tool) and Soriah.</p>
<p>The largest difference between &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221; and his previous catalog is in general tone. This album feels far more tethered to the human spirit, where as older albums often feel like soundtracks to natural phenomenon: the sounds a dying star or the cold mutterings of deep forgotten caverns. The inclusion of prominent human voices makes this feel like a solemn religious experience, a bit like a dark hymn in remembrance of a dead Medieval crusader.  These sounds are a ritual.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F90827606&amp;color=000000&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true"></iframe></p>
<p>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/salz/6230872740/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">s.alt</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power" data-wpel-link="internal">Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lycia, &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221;</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/lycia-quiet-moments</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/lycia-quiet-moments#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 22:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lycia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1336392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The legendary ethereal band Lycia returns with &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221;, their first full length CD in over ten years. It is comforting to see the return of a band so close to my heart. Despite having been inactive so long, they&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/lycia-quiet-moments" data-wpel-link="internal">Lycia, &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The legendary ethereal band <a href="https://www.facebook.com/OFFICIAL.LYCIA" title="Lycia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">Lycia</a> returns with &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221;, their first full length CD in over ten years. It is comforting to see the return of a band so close to my heart. Despite having been inactive so long, they seemed to pick up right where they left off, while pushing firmly into even quieter ambient territory.</p>
<p>&#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221; comes at an interesting time, when a lot of music has been appearing that is, very obviously, highly influenced by the sound Lycia represented so strongly in the 1990&#8217;s. Lycia utterly defined ethereal music, &#8220;Cold&#8221; being the perfect album for listening to during dark, gentle thunderstorms. Their music is both haunting and introspective, the perfect hymns for sad, longing ghosts. &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221; continues in this vein, but moves into even more gentle territory with some tracks that are strictly ambient in nature. This album feels even more introspective than their past work, which is a formidable accomplishment. The ambient pieces are organic and natural.</p>
<p>&#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221; is a return to form that makes the wait worthwhile. Hopefully it represents Lycia&#8217;s return and we can expect more to come. For existing Lycia fans, &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221; is a monumental release, one of their best. I would not be surprised to learn this came out somewhere between &#8220;A Day In The Stark Corner&#8221; and &#8220;Cold&#8221;, which represent Lycia&#8217;s high point. For new fans interested in dark, ethereal music: Lycia is the best there is, and &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221; represents this quintessentially.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/lycia-quiet-moments" data-wpel-link="internal">Lycia, &#8220;Quiet Moments&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/lycia-quiet-moments/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
