<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Industrial - Bottle Imp Productions</title>
	<atom:link href="/genres/industrial/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Independent Record Label - Ambient / Post-industrial / Neoclassical</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 15:09:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/bottleimp-144-120x120.png</url>
	<title>Industrial - Bottle Imp Productions</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>New Music Roundup &#8211; August 2018</title>
		<link>/blog/new-music-roundup-august-2018</link>
					<comments>/blog/new-music-roundup-august-2018#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 20:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castle if]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john bergin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keygen church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[master boot record]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uniform]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1981574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KEYGEN CHURCH KEYGEN CHURCH is a side project from synth-metal sorcerer MASTER BOOT RECORD. This album shifts from the heavy synth work to pianos and organs and it seriously evokes the mood of Castlevania: Symphony of the Night, for those&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/new-music-roundup-august-2018" data-wpel-link="internal">New Music Roundup &#8211; August 2018</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>KEYGEN CHURCH</strong></p>
<p>KEYGEN CHURCH is a side project from synth-metal sorcerer MASTER BOOT RECORD. This album shifts from the heavy synth work to pianos and organs and it seriously evokes the mood of Castlevania: Symphony of the Night, for those of you who remember that amazing game on the original PlayStation.</p>
<p><a href="https://keygenchurch.bandcamp.com/album/-" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">Get it on Bandcamp</a></p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1355848298/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless=""><a href="http://keygenchurch.bandcamp.com/album/-" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">by KEYGEN CHURCH</a></iframe></p>
<p><strong>John Bergin, &#8220;KILLER&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>John Bergin has been releasing rich, understated music for over 20 years. Back in the 90s he released albums under the band names Trust Obey and C17H19No3, both of which were built around cinematic and literary worlds, some of which accompanied actual stories and books, so of which didn&#8217;t. In all cases, the audio was a rich tapestry entrenched in conceptually rich worlds. With KILLER, the same thing applies, this time the setting is 90&#8217;s era cyberpunk against a psychological suspense thriller. Needless to say, I highly recommend this.</p>
<p><a href="https://johnbergin.bandcamp.com/album/killer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">Get it on Bandcamp</a></p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2268638840/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless=""><a href="http://johnbergin.bandcamp.com/album/killer" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">KILLER by John Bergin</a></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Castle If, &#8220;Sector 03&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Castle If is a project by Jess Forrest who has a fair sized catalog of albums now, this one being a high point for me. All of her work is made with rich analog synth work, but the character in this one is really fantastic. The analog washes are almost reminiscent of Kraftwerk, and the added, modulated vocals hammer home that comparison. However, where Kraftwerk was an exploration of machines and robots, this is far more emotive. There is still a strong tribute to machines present in the content, but stylistically we&#8217;re dealing with something much more human. Needless to say if you like Kraftwerk , it is worth a spin, but it also has an early Chris &amp; Cosey vibe.</p>
<p><a href="https://castleif.bandcamp.com/album/sector-03" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">Get it on Bandcamp</a></p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1824019276/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless=""><a href="http://castleif.bandcamp.com/album/sector-03" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Sector 03 by Castle If</a></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Uniform, &#8220;The Long Walk</strong>Get it on Bandcamp</p>
<p>Uniform&#8217;s &#8220;The Long Walk&#8221; is the best they&#8217;ve released so far, in my opinion, and that&#8217;s a bold statement considering what they&#8217;ve released in the past. It is angry. It is brutal. It is dark. It is intersecting my punk rock attitude with that sharp industrial music edge that I love. This stands out in rage and quality, in an era where I find myself listening to a lot of angry music.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3686192367/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless=""><a href="http://unifuckingform.bandcamp.com/album/the-long-walk" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">The Long Walk by Uniform</a></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/new-music-roundup-august-2018" data-wpel-link="internal">New Music Roundup &#8211; August 2018</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/new-music-roundup-august-2018/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AMNION on Inferno Compilation by Wychdoktor</title>
		<link>/news/amnion-inferno-compilation-wychdoktor</link>
					<comments>/news/amnion-inferno-compilation-wychdoktor#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 13:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amnion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wychdoktor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1981535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Canada based industrial musician Wychdoktor released a blisteringly dark compilation that features AMNION titled Inferno. Available on CD-R via Bandcamp. Inferno by Wychdoktor</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/amnion-inferno-compilation-wychdoktor" data-wpel-link="internal">AMNION on Inferno Compilation by Wychdoktor</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada based industrial musician Wychdoktor released a blisteringly dark compilation that features <a href="/artists/amnion" data-wpel-link="internal">AMNION</a> titled <a href="https://wychdoktor.bandcamp.com/album/inferno" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Inferno</a>. Available on CD-R via Bandcamp. </p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2999855448/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless><a href="http://wychdoktor.bandcamp.com/album/inferno" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Inferno by Wychdoktor</a></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/amnion-inferno-compilation-wychdoktor" data-wpel-link="internal">AMNION on Inferno Compilation by Wychdoktor</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/amnion-inferno-compilation-wychdoktor/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AMNION remix on new Wychdoktor album</title>
		<link>/news/amnion-remix-on-new-wychdoktor-album-ritual</link>
					<comments>/news/amnion-remix-on-new-wychdoktor-album-ritual#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 20:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amnion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wychdoktor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1702847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The new album by Wychdoktor, &#8220;Ritual&#8221;, features a remix by AMNION. Really strong, rhythmic industrial release, worth taking a listen. Ritual by Wychdoktor</p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/amnion-remix-on-new-wychdoktor-album-ritual" data-wpel-link="internal">AMNION remix on new Wychdoktor album</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new album by <a href="http://wychdoktor.bandcamp.com/" title="Wychdoktor" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Wychdoktor</a>, &#8220;Ritual&#8221;, features a <a href="http://wychdoktor.bandcamp.com/track/journey-to-the-heart-of-the-abyss-amnion-remix" title="remix by AMNION" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">remix by AMNIO</a>N. Really strong, rhythmic industrial release, worth taking a listen.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 42px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1245850220/size=small/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=18/transparent=true/" seamless><a href="http://wychdoktor.bandcamp.com/album/ritual" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Ritual by Wychdoktor</a></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/news/amnion-remix-on-new-wychdoktor-album-ritual" data-wpel-link="internal">AMNION remix on new Wychdoktor album</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/news/amnion-remix-on-new-wychdoktor-album-ritual/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Skinny Puppy, &#8220;Weapon&#8221;</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/skinny-puppy-weapon</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/skinny-puppy-weapon#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 20:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[download]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metropolis records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skinny puppy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Subconscious Communications]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1216110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So here we are, it is 2013 and Skinny Puppy releases a new album, this time titled, &#8220;Weapon&#8221;. Every time one of these albums comes out I feel compelled to listen to it, and be grumpy about it because everything&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/skinny-puppy-weapon" data-wpel-link="internal">Skinny Puppy, &#8220;Weapon&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So here we are, it is 2013 and Skinny Puppy releases a new album, this time titled, &#8220;Weapon&#8221;. Every time one of these albums comes out I feel compelled to listen to it, and be grumpy about it because everything I enjoyed about the early part of Skinny Puppy&#8217;s career is gone and is replaced with a musical style I am simply not enthusiastic about. Skinny Puppy was a band so strongly influential to my early interest in music, I can&#8217;t ever steer clear and have to at least give anything they do a  chance. After the past two albums, which were not terrible but didn&#8217;t gel with me very well, I approached &#8220;Weapon&#8221; with unfairly low expectations. After letting it churn around in my head for a while, I&#8217;ve found there are some things to really like here.</p>
<p>I want to take some space to talk about Skinny Puppy, where they&#8217;ve been and how we got to &#8220;Weapon&#8221;. These guys started kicking out this post-punk crazy music in 1982, making this band more than 30 years old now. In that 30 years, their career has been divided into two major parts: before and after the various catastrophes of the mid-1990&#8217;s, which included the death of their keyboardist Dwayne Goettel. This was a critical turning point. To start with, the band lost a major contributor and friend. In a three person band, this is significant. This catastrophe was further compounded by other calamities including record label drama, a fire in the recording studio and vocalist Ogre leaving the band (prior to Goettel&#8217;s passing). After some time, after the record had been shelved for a while, it was released. It was the first album that pointed in a very stark artistic direction that parted ways with the wall-of-sound, discordant industrial/noise symphony that climaxed with the previous album, &#8220;Last Rights&#8221; (still a personal favorite, though I love the entire early catalog).</p>
<p>&#8220;The Process&#8221; was released in 1996. Listening to it, it is immediately obvious that the band radically changed directions. There were a few songs that had some qualities reminiscent of the previous work, but on the whole, this was new territory for the band. There were crunchy metal guitars, four-to-the-floor dance beats, really clean production and a lot greater pop appeal. &#8220;The Process&#8221; was still edgy music, but it did not sit comfortably in their older catalog. Not to suggest the older catalog didn&#8217;t evolve from conception, it most certainly did. You could hear, with each album, a growth in their niche, the production became nuanced, with more layers and more refinement.  &#8220;The Process&#8221; comes out and there is no evolution here: It is just flat out different. Personally speaking, I still enjoyed &#8220;The Process&#8221;, but I was a very loyal fan at the time and the band could release anything and I&#8217;d enjoy it. Even had said that, a few tracks like &#8220;Candle&#8221; grated my nerves a tad.</p>
<p>Fast forward to 2000, Key and Ogre resurrect the band, do some shows, put out an album and do tours. The new material is an evolution from the sound established with &#8220;The Process&#8221;. In truth, the newer albums were vastly superior, cleaner, more tightly produced, showing a strong modern approach to electronic music production. By 2004 when &#8220;The Greater Wrong of the Right&#8221; came out, I was over it. As an old school fan, the new style just didn&#8217;t work for me. Was it good music? Sure. But on the whole, my primary criticism was that Skinny Puppy now sounded like bands that previously been inspired by Skinny Puppy, and they weren&#8217;t necessarily doing this as well as bands that had done it before them. In the 90&#8217;s there were so many industrial bands trying to replace Skinny Puppy as the powerhouse of industrial music and while many good bands came of this, none of them came close. The &#8220;industrial&#8221; style slowly degraded into cyber-goth four-to-the-flour trance techno with gritty synths and grunty vocals (also imitating Ogre&#8217;s vocal style). Skinny Puppy&#8217;s new albums just felt like another one of these albums to me, despite being able to acknowledge that their new albums were, in fact, vastly superior compositions with vastly super production. I still found a few tracks off the new albums to be decent to listen to, but they didn&#8217;t feel very inspired or very innovative. Somewhere in all this my romance with this legendary band was compartmentalized.</p>
<p>All this exposition is to make a point here: This change in style took place circa 1994, which was 19 years ago. The band was 12 years old at the time. This means Skinny Puppy has been running with this new style quite a bit longer than they had the previous style. This all assuming you measure things in years, as prior to &#8220;The Process&#8221;, the band was way more prolific up to &#8220;Last Rights&#8221;. Between 1984 and 1992, they released nine albums, and since then only five. Still, we&#8217;re talking about a big generation gap and it&#8217;s been over twenty years since &#8220;Last Rights&#8221; was released. This stopped being &#8220;the new Skinny Puppy&#8221; a long time ago. At some point while listening to &#8220;Weapon&#8221;, probably when the new version of &#8220;Solvent&#8221; I started milling over this fact in my head and it put some serious context to the album for me.</p>
<p>Having now started to listen to &#8220;Weapon&#8221; through this new perspective, I started hearing things that really call back to Skinny Puppy of the 80&#8217;s. This really resonated for me on the third track of the album, &#8220;SoLvo&#8221;, particularly as it closed out with the grainy echoes and tape loops. The synth work through out the song is very reminiscent of Skinny Puppy pre-1992, particularly in the spaces, transitions, vocal effects, etc. There is a real atmosphere that teleports me back to albums like &#8220;Too Dark Park&#8221;. I&#8217;m not trying to convince anyone this album sounds like an old school Puppy album, but there is crack shining through that flickers a nostalgic feeling. In that, I identify with the modern Skinny Puppy in ways I never could before.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:track:1Uu9weKq9KbJ51HXylRJe1" width="300" height="80" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8220;SoLvo&#8221; then transitions into &#8220;gLowbeL&#8221;, a song I can&#8217;t even begin to understand with its silly opening synth lines that sound like an organ grinder. The album hits and misses like this, with each strong song paired with something forgettable or even nerve grating.</p>
<p>All this is amplified, of course, by the inclusion of them recreating one of their older songs, &#8220;Solvent&#8221;. Which is an interesting experiment, because this is lodged right into the center of the album, a nice big slab of real old school Skinny Puppy sandwiched between a bunch of really clean, new recordings. Despite this being a modern recreation of an old song, it still feels mostly in-congruent, but I think it works very well to illustrate the tone of the album.</p>
<p>Lyrically, Ogre&#8217;s style has evolved over the years. The vocal styling and lyrical content on &#8220;Weapon&#8221; largely match what Ogre&#8217;s been doing since the late 90&#8217;s: Somewhat more melodic, with unusual but coherent effects and politically charge themes. Occasionally he dips into Reznor-ish goofiness along the lines of my favorite Nine Inch Nails lyric of all time: &#8220;flip flop flip flop flip&#8221;, in particular on my favorite new song &#8220;SoLvo&#8221; where the main refrain is &#8220;Screw it!&#8221;, which punctuates a number of lines in the song. Fortunately, it isn&#8217;t too distracting and Ogre&#8217;s lyrics otherwise fit the musical content perfectly, and are as thought provoking as usual.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m left at an impasse. I love Skinny Puppy, and I realize I&#8217;ve been a fan for over twenty years. These guys are legends to me, now putting out albums that don&#8217;t excite me like their albums used to. Not meant to be a statement to mark me as an old man as I am comfortably in my thirties, but I do like to imagine old man Ogre and Grandpa Key nerding out in their studio, cranking out albums that, above all else, they love making. This love of the craft reflects on &#8220;Weapon&#8221;. Thinking about that along with my other personal revelations, I find a warm comfort in &#8220;Weapon&#8221; that I haven&#8217;t found in a Skinny Puppy album for many years. Speaking as a put-off old school fan, Skinny Puppy&#8217;s &#8220;Weapon&#8221; is actually refreshing, and I highly recommend this album to my jaded peers. This one is actually pretty solid!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/skinny-puppy-weapon" data-wpel-link="internal">Skinny Puppy, &#8220;Weapon&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/skinny-puppy-weapon/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ohgr, &#8220;Devils In My Details&#8221;</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/ohgr-devils-in-my-details</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/ohgr-devils-in-my-details#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 19:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nivek ogre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ohgr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skinny puppy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.last.fm/user/obsequious/journal/2008/11/10/29rcu8_ohgr%2C_%22devils_in_my_details%22</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Buried inside of me is a die hard Skinny Puppy fan that simply will not go away. In my youth, Skinny Puppy could do no wrong. I was so excited about “The Process” that I even forgave some of the&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/ohgr-devils-in-my-details" data-wpel-link="internal">Ohgr, &#8220;Devils In My Details&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Buried inside of me is a die hard Skinny Puppy fan that simply will not go away. In my youth, Skinny Puppy could do no wrong. I was so excited about “The Process” that I even forgave some of the extremely weak moments on the disc simply because it was new Skinny Puppy material. You know, I forgave it even though it scarcely sounded like a Skinny Puppy record. But, I was a fan. I owned the whole catalog, had most of the singles and B-sides, and even owned some weird collector’s stuff. I even helped run the first big Skinny Puppy website. It is sufficient to say that had I never discovered Skinny Puppy, my musical world may never widened the way it did.</p>
<p>So what happened? Well, for one, my musical tastes evolved. I grew up a bit, quit being such a damned rivethead, and frankly, my tastes mellowed. Well, they got mellow and they got extreme, but extreme where the likes of Skinny Puppy would never go. Even cEvin Key’s Download project got too weak for me, after the departure of Mark Spybey, the last interesting component after the death of Puppy keyboardist Dwayne Goettel.</p>
<p>In comes a new decade and this Skinny Puppy revival. Ogre releases long awaited solo material as ohGr, and new Puppy albums start to arrive. I can’t say I enjoyed any of it too much. Ohgr’s first disc, “Welt”, was kind of a winner to me, despite it not living up to expectations. But, it isn’t fair to critique works based on expectations. I enjoyed the pop hooks and clever vocal processing. Honestly, I like the new singing Ogre more than the old tortured grunting Ogre.</p>
<p>It seems clear that “Devils In My Details” is an attempt to go back to the old, gritty Skinny Puppy styling. This is great, in my opinion, but it is not handled with the best effect on this record. For one, where is the confident Ogre vocal mix I was getting used to? The vocal work is really mushy and quiet. I love how it sounds when I can hear it, but it really is very quiet and muddy. I normally think Mark Walk is a very high quality producer, having enjoyed other albums he engineered like the Ruby album, so I have to suspect this low mix is intentional and not oversight. I simply can’t see what the point is, as it makes some of the songs really irritating to listen to. There are also a few tracks with annoying refrains, taking this demonic pop sensibility into a territory that is too silly and goofy to even redeem it as good tongue-in-cheek music. Think of David Tibet’s “rapping” on Current 93’s, “Crowleymass“. I liked the tongue-in-cheek on previous Ohgr outings, it just seems a little over played on a few of the tracks here.</p>
<p>Bear in mind, I say these things even though I think this is a great album. I will invariably listen to it on rotation for a long time. It has some great songs that have intense atmospheric depth, interesting IDM elements buried in the back, as well as memorable catches and great&nbsp;play-ability&nbsp; It is a nice throw back to the old Skinny Puppy sounds of albums like “Too Dark Park” and “Last Rights” mixed subtly with the older Ohgr albums. However, since it has so many serious faults, what will happen is individual songs will quickly get chopped from my playlists and I’ll end up only listening to the same three songs forever. If you’re a fan of Skinny Puppy, new or old, you absolutely should check out this album and form your own opinion. Chances are good you will enjoy it, faults and all. If you’re a fan of older gritty styles of industrial music, it might also be a worthwhile investment of your time and cash.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/ohgr-devils-in-my-details" data-wpel-link="internal">Ohgr, &#8220;Devils In My Details&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/ohgr-devils-in-my-details/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
