<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Reviews - Bottle Imp Productions</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/reviews-2/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/reviews-2</link>
	<description>Independent Record Label - Ambient / Post-industrial / Neoclassical</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:22:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/bottleimp-144-120x120.png</url>
	<title>Reviews - Bottle Imp Productions</title>
	<link>/category/reviews-2</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Sextile, &#8220;A Thousand Hands&#8221; Review</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/sextile-a-thousand-hands-review</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/sextile-a-thousand-hands-review#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 15:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[felte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sextile]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1981415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Before anything can be said about how good the debut album, &#8220;A Thousand Hands&#8221;, by Sextile is, I feel compelled to note that Felte is quickly becoming a new favorite record label. It should have been clear that I am&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/sextile-a-thousand-hands-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Sextile, &#8220;A Thousand Hands&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before anything can be said about how good the debut album, &#8220;A Thousand Hands&#8221;, by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sextileband" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">Sextile</a> is, I feel compelled to note that <a href="https://felte.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">Felte </a>is quickly becoming a new favorite record label. It should have been clear that I am a huge fan of Ritual Howl&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="/reviews-2/ritual-howls-turkish-leather-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Turkish Leather</a>&#8220;. Since, I&#8217;ve been keeping an eye on Felte, and caught the new release by Sextile which is also a wonderfully assembled, nostalgic feeling post-punk album.</p>
<p>The primary challenge in reviewing an album like &#8220;A Thousand Hands&#8221; is that I am ultimately going to spend a lot of time talking about things I find familiar with it, bands to compare it to and what influences I detect. This invariably feels like I am suggesting that this album isn&#8217;t terribly original and is entirely derivative. I want to emphasize that this is not how I feel about Sextile at all. It is nostalgic and the band&#8217;s influences are obvious to anyone familiar with them, but Sextile has created a nice, original piece of work that puts their influences to work sculpting their own brand.</p>
<p>Imagine the witch-iest of black cauldrons. Throw in a slice of Bauhaus, a portion of The Birthday Party, a sprinkle of Death In June&#8217;s &#8220;The Guilty Have No Pride&#8221;, a dash of Coil&#8217;s &#8220;Scatology&#8221;, some John Carpenter/Goblin-esque horror synthesizers and a cup of 80&#8217;s Wax Trax!-isms. You&#8217;re starting to imagine the flavor of Sextile&#8217;s brew.  This album swells methodically with all this mood and 80&#8217;s deathrock/post-punk vibe. Also, to state it plainly: it is done very well and is a really good album. It drips with nostalgic atmosphere, with just the right level of retro production that still provides a depth of clarity.</p>
<p>I am going to levy one piece of criticism, not to be taken harshly: This album wears a lot of influences on its sleeves, but fails to rise up to those predecessors. It sort of lacks Bauhaus&#8217; passion, Death In June&#8217;s soul and Coil&#8217;s mysticism. All those things are present, but it feels like a &#8220;jack of all trades&#8221; sort of situation, and they don&#8217;t quite bring any of the strengths to the forefront. As a result, the album falls just short of greatness, which will unfortunately keep it from ever being viewed as a genuine classic. This is the band&#8217;s debut, so there is a wealth of opportunity to grow. Not to suggest there aren&#8217;t some classic tracks. &#8220;Into the Unknown&#8221; and &#8220;Visions of You&#8221; are straight up fucking amazing songs that will sit in my playlists for years to come, but those couple tracks sit at the end of the album. Not that the journey to them is bad, as I don&#8217;t want to give that impression. Every second this album is spinning is an outstanding and beautifully atmospheric experience. I levy this criticism entirely as a gesture because if Sextile pushed the vibe of &#8220;Visions of You&#8221; into a whole album, they might have something that will stand the test of time.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t let any of that criticism slow you down. If you yearn for a return of rich, atmospheric gothic rock the way it is supposed to be done, you should already be listening to this album.</p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/217522552&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/sextile-a-thousand-hands-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Sextile, &#8220;A Thousand Hands&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/sextile-a-thousand-hands-review/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ritual Howls, &#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; Review</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/ritual-howls-turkish-leather-review</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/ritual-howls-turkish-leather-review#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 17:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ritual howls]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1981351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; by Ritual Howls is dark, post-punk, gothic rock the way it was meant to be done. These guys are representing Detroit in the best way imaginable: It is dark, gritty, properly brooding and utterly atmospheric. I am entirely&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/ritual-howls-turkish-leather-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Ritual Howls, &#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; by Ritual Howls is dark, post-punk, gothic rock the way it was meant to be done. These guys are representing Detroit in the best way imaginable: It is dark, gritty, properly brooding and utterly atmospheric.</p>
<p>I am entirely late to this party, this album has been out since last September and I just listened to it a few weeks ago. Even worse, band member Christopher Samuels has been a buddy for years. I met Bottle Imp&#8217;s&nbsp;<a title="Metria" href="/artists/metria" data-wpel-link="internal">Metria&#8217;s</a> David Cole by way of the pair&#8217;s early 00&#8217;s industrial, power electronic act <a href="http://www.discogs.com/artist/265782-Di_Sect" title="Di_sect on Discogs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow external" data-wpel-link="external">di_sect</a>. So I&#8217;ve been a fan for over ten years, anyway.</p>
<p>I picked up the vinyl from their label,&nbsp;Felte. Without saying anything else about the album, it is worth noting that this album begs to be played on vinyl. You get the digital version free with the record when you buy from their Bandcamp page, and Felte also sent a fantastic label sampler to download free.</p>
<p>&#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; is, as I noted above, rich and atmospheric, and has a very serious early 80&#8217;s vibe to it. The composition here is very&nbsp;modern, but the production and tone have all the space and depth of some of the best albums from 1979 to 1983, think Bauhaus or The Cure&#8217;s &#8220;Pornography&#8221;. This isn&#8217;t cheap imitation, though, these guys are really rocking it. This is music that sounds like Detroit at night.</p>
<p>&#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; is great night time listening, and should be outstanding club music. I&#8217;ve been stuck on this album for over a week now, and I don&#8217;t see that behavior slowing down any time soon.</p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/153512821&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/ritual-howls-turkish-leather-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Ritual Howls, &#8220;Turkish Leather&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/ritual-howls-turkish-leather-review/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNDISCLOSED, &#8220;7C858C&#8221; Review</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/undisclosed-7c858c-review</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/undisclosed-7c858c-review#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 21:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[7C858C]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anonymous]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1981347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;7C858C&#8221; is the first in the UNDISCLOSED series, an intriguing and compelling release concept curated by Headphone Commute. The idea is to find an existing, somewhat notable artist, strip away all branding and identity and let them release music that may&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/undisclosed-7c858c-review" data-wpel-link="internal">UNDISCLOSED, &#8220;7C858C&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;7C858C&#8221; is the first in the <a title="UNDISCLOSED sounds" href="http://undisclosedsounds.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">UNDISCLOSED</a> series, an intriguing and compelling release concept curated by <a title="Headphone Commute website" href="http://reviews.headphonecommute.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Headphone Commute</a>. The idea is to find an existing, somewhat notable artist, strip away all branding and identity and let them release music that may not fit stylistically what their normal audience might expect.  Interestingly, the lack of branding and identity creates a very distinct brand and identity, but that&#8217;s part of the appeal here.</p>
<p>HC is know for finding and sharing some of the best music currently out there, so him curating the series should make anyone want to listen to it anyway.  We have no idea who is behind 7C858C, but whoever it is has a great knack for Eno-esque ambient tracks. This isn&#8217;t a long release, hovering around twenty minutes, but it is the sort of ambient that makes you float. The sonic textures are super rich and engrossing.</p>
<p>Perhaps the only negative aspect here is we never get to find out who it is! I&#8217;m dying to know, but that&#8217;s all part of the charm and mystery. Plus, at $1.99 for the album with the &#8220;pay what you want&#8221; Bandcamp option available, it is worth plunking your cash down just so we can see this series continue. My hope is that many more musical genres get explored with this concept and that UNDISCLOSED doesn&#8217;t just become a clever brand of ambient music. Not that there is anything wrong with it remaining all ambient music, it just feels like this could explore some other intense territory.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2163450738/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" width="300" height="150" seamless=""><a href="http://undisclosedsounds.bandcamp.com/album/7c858c" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">7C858C by UNDISCLOSED</a></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/undisclosed-7c858c-review" data-wpel-link="internal">UNDISCLOSED, &#8220;7C858C&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/undisclosed-7c858c-review/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kreng, &#8220;The Summoner&#8221; Review</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/kreng-summoner-review</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/kreng-summoner-review#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 16:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kreng]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miasmah]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1981342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kreng might make the scariest music on Earth. This is a bold statement when I consider my listening habits, but I find myself pleasantly disturbed sitting here listening to Kreng&#8217;s new masterpiece, &#8220;The Summoner&#8221;. Most of the tracks are named&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/kreng-summoner-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Kreng, &#8220;The Summoner&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kreng might make the scariest music on Earth. This is a bold statement when I consider my listening habits, but I find myself pleasantly disturbed sitting here listening to Kreng&#8217;s new masterpiece, &#8220;The Summoner&#8221;.</p>
<p>Most of the tracks are named for one of the stages of grief, and that theme sits well. &#8220;The Summoner&#8221; is potent, in large part due to Kreng&#8217;s usage of volume dynamics. He slowly builds musical landscapes with subtle, quiet ambiance and very quickly brings in loud, unsettling strings. By &#8220;unsettling&#8221;, I mean absolutely gorgeous, but Kreng&#8217;s mastery over tension and mood rivals even artists like David Lynch.</p>
<p>Kreng&#8217;s &#8220;The Summoner&#8221; is a lucid and contemplative nightmare, as beautiful as it is tense. It is also worth noting that the vinyl is gorgeous and worth the price alone.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="100%" height="20" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/187119212&amp;color=ff5500&amp;inverse=false&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_user=true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/kreng-summoner-review" data-wpel-link="internal">Kreng, &#8220;The Summoner&#8221; Review</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/kreng-summoner-review/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>20,000 Days on Earth: A look at Nick Cave&#8217;s Creative Process</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/20000-days-earth-look-nick-cave</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/20000-days-earth-look-nick-cave#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 15:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Movie Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iain Forsyth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nick cave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the bad seeds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1966636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I had an interesting opportunity to attend the L.A. premier of the new film &#8220;20,000 Days on Earth&#8221;, a sort of stylish documentary film about Bad Seeds front man, Nick Cave. We were shown the film, then Nick Cave came&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/20000-days-earth-look-nick-cave" data-wpel-link="internal">20,000 Days on Earth: A look at Nick Cave&#8217;s Creative Process</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had an interesting opportunity to attend the L.A. premier of the new film &#8220;20,000 Days on Earth&#8221;, a sort of stylish documentary film about Bad Seeds front man, Nick Cave. We were shown the film, then Nick Cave came out and did a Q&#038;A mixed with a solo performance, that yielded some interesting insight into the film itself. The primary take away from the Q&#038;A is that this film isn&#8217;t precisely a documentary, and if it were a typical &#8220;rock &#8216;n roll&#8221; documentary, Cave would not have agreed to do it. </p>
<p>Instead, the film is an intimate view into Nick Cave&#8217;s creative persona and creative process, done in a way as to not de-mystify the Nick Cave persona. There are a few interesting scenes where it shows Cave driving with old collaborators in the car with him, and they&#8217;re candidly discussing various topics. Notably, he was visited by Kylie Minogue and his former Bad Seeds guitarist, Blixa Bargeld from Einstürzende Neubauten. This film also has one of the best title sequences ever, showing a montage of Cave&#8217;s life alongside the number of days passing in his life from 1 to 20,000. </p>
<p>The film apparently was built around a studio recording the director did of The Bad Seeds recording &#8220;Higgs Boson Blues&#8221; from the latest album &#8220;Push the Sky Away&#8221;. It was very well filmed and showed incredible insight into how Nick Cave and The Bad Seeds work as a band and put together their songs. Hearing this cut before it went through the mixing / mastering process, and watching Cave sort of play conductor to his orchestra is quite compelling, and honestly I could probably watch an entire film of them recording the entire album. The film also shows a lot of footage of the band jamming and feeling out new songs, showing Warren Ellis fiddling with electronic gear and effects, and Nick Cave working to get his lyrics a musical canvas. </p>
<p>&#8220;20,000 Days on Earth&#8221; is absolutely worth watching if you&#8217;re interested in getting a glimpse into the creative process of Nick Cave and the Bad Seeds. It certainly does not go too deep into Nick Cave&#8217;s personal life, as it seems he is very protective of his creative brand and persona, but that works as an asset to this film which is focused on the creative process. Nothing is demystified, but we are treated with an interesting narrative.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="853" height="480" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/VM-p8VPpWOQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/20000-days-earth-look-nick-cave" data-wpel-link="internal">20,000 Days on Earth: A look at Nick Cave&#8217;s Creative Process</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/20000-days-earth-look-nick-cave/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adrian Aniol, &#8220;Obscura&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 15:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obscura]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1770900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Obscura&#8221; is an original score composed by Adrian Aniol for a theatre production. This must have been a frightening production as the music is utterly dark, tense and horrifying. This music is scary in the same way the Penderecki compositions&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura" data-wpel-link="internal">Adrian Aniol, &#8220;Obscura&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Obscura&#8221; is an original score composed by <a title="Adrian Aniol" href="https://adriananiol.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Adrian Aniol</a> for a theatre production. This must have been a frightening production as the music is utterly dark, tense and horrifying. This music is scary in the same way the Penderecki compositions used in Stanley Kubrick&#8217;s &#8220;The Shining&#8221; is scary. Its completely suspenseful, and keeps you moving frame-by-frame, wondering what hides behind the next corner, or under the bed. Aniol is no stranger to dark compositions, but this one turns the darkness up to eleven. This is certainly worth the $5 USD it costs to download from his <a title="Bandcamp" href="https://adriananiol.bandcamp.com/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Bandcamp</a>. And while you&#8217;re there, listen to his other works as they are all similarly wonderful.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura" data-wpel-link="internal">Adrian Aniol, &#8220;Obscura&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/adrian-aniol-obscura/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 15:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drudge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinkish black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relapse records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sword and sorcery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1678189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The new album by Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221; is an epic work that could be the soundtrack to a bad ass, early 80&#8217;s Sword and Sorcery flick. This is heavy, drudge metal, layered with waves of vintage filter&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground" data-wpel-link="internal">Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new album by Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221; is an epic work that could be the soundtrack to a bad ass, early 80&#8217;s Sword and Sorcery flick. This is heavy, drudge metal, layered with waves of vintage filter sweeps that evoke images of battles, journeys to the underworld and heroic deaths. Amazingly, this album that sits so solidly in the area of doom metal is entirely devoid of any guitars. The music is entirely performed by a duo, one on a drum kit and the other on a rack of synthesizers. This album is still blisteringly heavy, and you never miss the guitars for a second. &#8220;Razed to the Ground&#8221; is highly dynamic, with incredible song structure.</p>
<p>The only unfortunate reality here is that Pinkish Black&#8217;s &#8220;Razed to the Ground&#8221; is not, in fact, the soundtrack to some early 80&#8217;s Sword and Sorcery epic. Here&#8217;s to hoping this obvious marriage could occur some day!</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/106472936&amp;color=000000&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground" data-wpel-link="internal">Pinkish Black, &#8220;Razed To The Ground&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/pinkish-black-razed-ground/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Row Boat&#8217;s &#8220;ETT&#8221; reviewed by Stationary Travels</title>
		<link>/reviews-2/row-boats-ett-reviewed-stationary-travels</link>
					<comments>/reviews-2/row-boats-ett-reviewed-stationary-travels#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 16:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[row boat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stationary travels]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1486891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Row Boat&#8217;s new full length album, &#8220;ETT&#8221;, was reviewed by Stationary Travels, a nice blog that focuses on ambient, post-rock and modern classical music. As enjoyable as were the EPs, ”Romance” and “Svaret är ja”, “ETT” unfurls the full scope&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/row-boats-ett-reviewed-stationary-travels" data-wpel-link="internal">Row Boat&#8217;s &#8220;ETT&#8221; reviewed by Stationary Travels</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Row Boat&#8217;s new full length album, &#8220;ETT&#8221;, was reviewed by Stationary Travels, a nice blog that focuses on ambient, post-rock and modern classical music. </p>
<blockquote><p>As enjoyable as were the EPs,  ”Romance” and “Svaret är ja”, “ETT” unfurls the full scope and power of Mark’s creative vision and it arrives as a significant and ear-catching contribution in an increasingly crowded field. </p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://stationarytravels.wordpress.com/2013/09/10/album-review-ett-by-row-boat-bottle-imp-productions/" title="Stationary Travels" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Read the full review at Stationary Travels</a>. </p>
<p>The post <a href="/reviews-2/row-boats-ett-reviewed-stationary-travels" data-wpel-link="internal">Row Boat&#8217;s &#8220;ETT&#8221; reviewed by Stationary Travels</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/reviews-2/row-boats-ett-reviewed-stationary-travels/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 20:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chelsea wolfe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1414360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s album &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221; is epic, bold, ethereal and beautiful. This is a full fledged, fully realized rock album, covering all the gothic torch-bearing attributes one could ever hope to find in one album. The instrument selection bounces&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty" data-wpel-link="internal">Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s album &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221; is epic, bold, ethereal and beautiful. This is a full fledged, fully realized rock album, covering all the gothic torch-bearing attributes one could ever hope to find in one album. </p>
<p>The instrument selection bounces around a fair bit song to song, but it does not distract from the cohesiveness of the overall composition. A few songs use pulsing electronics with programmed percussion, where others use organic drum kits. Strings ebb and flow and each song creates its own unique palette of sounds. </p>
<p>Each song has a sublime yet tenebrous quality to it, but it bounces around stylistically. The fourth track, &#8220;The Warden&#8221;, starts out with a pulsing electronic rhythm and slowly opens up into a song that would be at home on a 1980&#8217;s album by The Legendary Pink Dots. Except, of course, minus the enigmatic Edward Ka-spel and add the mysteriously haunting Chelsea Wolfe, whose ghostly voice carries the strength of the song. &#8220;The Warden&#8221; transitions into &#8220;Destruction Makes the World Burn Brighter&#8221;, a more up-tempo piece that would sit comfortably on the soundtrack for &#8220;Twin Peaks&#8221;. This type of surreal juxtaposition occurs a few times, and it is never jarring: The album moves on and you are pulled deep into Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s dark, haunted world. </p>
<p>Chelsea Wolfe&#8217;s &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221; is one of the very best albums of 2013. Its also one of the best from her own catalog, which is a formidable feat in itself, since all of her albums are similarly amazing. The strong composition, the strength of Wolfe&#8217;s voice and the extremely tight production push the album into remarkable territories. This is an album you&#8217;ll listen to on repeat.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 42px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1972857446/size=small/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/transparent=true/" seamless><a href="http://chelseawolfe.bandcamp.com/album/pain-is-beauty" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Pain is Beauty by CHELSEA WOLFE</a></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty" data-wpel-link="internal">Chelsea Wolfe, &#8220;Pain Is Beauty&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/chelsea-wolfe-pain-beauty/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</title>
		<link>/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power</link>
					<comments>/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Tuttle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jarboe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lustmord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maynard James Keenan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1396246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Lustmord&#8217;s &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221; is an appropriately potent album that departs musically from the drones that make up his previous albums. This album still has Lustmord&#8217;s signature drones and dark ambiance, but is accompanied by extremely rich vocal performances.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power" data-wpel-link="internal">Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.lustmord.com/" title="Lustmord" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">Lustmord&#8217;s</a> &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221; is an appropriately potent album that departs musically from the drones that make up his previous albums.  This album still has Lustmord&#8217;s signature drones and dark ambiance, but is accompanied by extremely rich vocal performances. The vocals are provided by an assortment of guest vocalists including Aina Skinnes Olsen, Jarboe (from Swans), Maynard James Keenan (from Tool) and Soriah.</p>
<p>The largest difference between &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221; and his previous catalog is in general tone. This album feels far more tethered to the human spirit, where as older albums often feel like soundtracks to natural phenomenon: the sounds a dying star or the cold mutterings of deep forgotten caverns. The inclusion of prominent human voices makes this feel like a solemn religious experience, a bit like a dark hymn in remembrance of a dead Medieval crusader.  These sounds are a ritual.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F90827606&amp;color=000000&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true"></iframe></p>
<p>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/salz/6230872740/" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="external" rel="nofollow external noopener noreferrer">s.alt</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power" data-wpel-link="internal">Lustmord, &#8220;The Word as Power&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="/" data-wpel-link="internal">Bottle Imp Productions</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/music-reviews/lustmord-the-word-as-power/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
